Vishnu priya Katari

DevOps Engineer at Deloitte
6 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | Bangalore/Bengaluru | INR 7.20 Lac(s)

7989498445 priyavishnu.katari@gmail.com

¹¹ AWS DevOps Engineer seeking roles in Aws Services, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Terraform, Jenkins, Cicd Pipeline, Grafana, Github, Maven, application deployments, Load balancing, Autoscaling, cloud watch, UNIX/LINUX

WORK SUMMARY

AWS DevOps Engineer with 5+ years of experience working on services including EC2, 53, IAM, Load balancing, Autoscaling, cloud watch etc and also executing build pipelines using Jenkins and deployments using Docker, Kubernetes. Was responsible for Azure administration and operation across various platform (UNIX/LINUX and Windows) in the prior projects.

Industry: Management Consulting

Department : Engineering - Software & QA

Role: DevOps Engineer

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer May 2023 - Till Date **Deloitte**

AWS DevOps Engineer Mar 2020 - Apr 2023

Deloitte

AWS DevOps Engineer Mar 2020 - Apr 2023

Deloitte

* Having experience using DevOps tools including GIT, Bit Bucket, Jenkins, Maven, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform and AWS Cloud. * Working with various AWS services like Creating EC2 Instances, and configuring all web Services like EC2, 53 bucket, IAM, EKS, Elastic Load balancers, Autoscaling, cloud watch etc * Provisioning of infrastructure using Terraform to create VPC, VPC Peering, Subnet, Security Groups, Route Table, NAT Gateway, 53, EC2, IAM, ELB, Route 53, SNS, SQS, RDS etc * Handled application deployments by building docker images and deploying to Kubernetes. * Possess good knowledge in creating and launching EC2 instances using AMI'S and snapshots for the backups. * Knowledge of IAM services to create user's groups, create users, attaching user to the group, sign roles and define polices. * Created VPC, subnets, NAT gateways, Internet gateways, Peering, route Tables. * Created S3 bucket configured S3 bucket with various life cycle policies to archive the infrequently accessed data to storage classes

based on requirement. * Hands on experience on AWS CLI. * Developed Automated CI/CD Pipelines for deployment using Jenkins and AWS Code PIPELINE. * Created Containers of MYSQL, Redis, Apache webserver on docker

Azure Infra Admin Aug 2017 - Feb 2020

1KNOT9 India Solutions

- * Cloud Administrator on MS Azure configuring VMs, Accounts and Resource Groups. * Experience working on VNET Peering on VMs between same, differnent networks and regions.
- * Experience setting up Storage accounts and shared access to users using AccessKeys. * Run backups of data regularly and design new stored procedures * Maintaining system security by identifying vulnerable areas and providing protections * Install the required systems and security tools to provide protection * Basic knowledge on Azure Active Directory.

PROJECT DETAILS

Supply Chain portal(SCP) for LandMark

Mar 2020 to Till Date

Client: Deloitte

Nature of Employment : Full Time

Project Details:

② Setup Cloud infrastructure on AWS using Terraform provisioning for services - EC2, IAM, VPC, Autos calling, ELB, 53, and AWS CLI. ② Implemented Groovy based Jenkins file for automating Cl-CD process. ② Created AMI images, EC2 Instances, attach Volumes to Ec2 Instances using AWS CLI and GU]. ② Created events in s3 buckets and modify permissions. Create and configure S3 bucket with restricted policies. ② Cross Account perrnissioning using IAM User & Roles. ② Implemented IAM policies and Roles as per organization requirement. ② Implemented Docker for creating development environment and QA environment. ② Implemented build process with tool like Maven. ② Creating and managing Virtual Machines and Templates, Worked with clones and snapshots of Virtual Machines Windows and Linux servers. Unified Data Management Aug 2017 - Feb 2020 Azure Infra Admin ② Worked as Cloud Administrator on Microsoft Azure,involved in configuring virtual machines, storage accourits, resource groups.

Unified Data Management

Oct 2017 to Jan 2020

Client : Softqube Technologies **Nature of Employment :** Full Time

Project Details:

The UDM stores subscriber information externally where in all the details regarding the user equipment is stored - the SIM details and the user details. The data of the user is authenticated by Home Location Register (HLR) to Visitor Location Register (VLR).

EDUCATION DETAILS

U.G.

B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) 2009

Anna University

IT SKILLS

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Jenkins, Cloud Watch		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Maven		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Docker		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Github,Grafana,Azure DevOps		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Kubernetes Linux		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Terraform, Unix, Cloud Watch		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Aws Lambda,CICD Pipelines		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
AWS(EC2, RDS, Route53, IAM, VPC, S3)		0	3 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
EKS, IAM Policies, S3 buckets		0	
Load Balancers, Autoscaling		0	

DESIRED JOB DETAILS

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full time US Work Status: Not Mentioned

Preferred Location: Bangalore/Bengaluru,Chennai

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Vishnu priya Katari

Gender: Female

Marital Status : Married

Date of Birth : 02 Jun 1988

Address: Ushodaya Pallavi, aptno: 110, Belathur, Kadugodi BANGALORE/BENGALURU-560067

Mobile: 7989498445(M)

Email ID: priyavishnu.katari@gmail.com